Naoto Abe

+46 76-346-5979 | naotoabe1@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/naotoabe/ | github.com/otoaneba

SUMMARY

Over 5 years of extensive experience at AT&T, the largest telecommunication company in the USA, with a focus on payment, billing, and agreements services in full-stack development. Recently relocated to Sweden for family reasons and eager to contribute to creating an innovative and sustainable environment.

EXPERIENCE

AT&T Atlanta, GA

Software Engineer

March 2020 - August 2023

- Dispatch Billing and Payment Pioneered a tracking feature that facilitated seamless detection and resolution of billing discrepancies. Developed billing and payment features for a full-stack application, supporting over 30,000 technicians and serving more than 100,000 customers. Achieved a remarkable increase in revenue, surpassing \$40 million.
- Digital Invoice and Agreements Automated the invoice and contract signing process by implementing mobile devices. This initiative not only improved customer satisfaction but also led to a significant reduction in manual labor costs. Successfully overhauled legacy code, resulting in a 35% reduction in code volume for both TypeScript and Swift.
- Customer History for Personalization Implemented a historical display of customers' purchases and services for technicians, enabling accurate and efficient diagnosis and personalized solutions.
- Agile Development Led the agile development team supporting a critical application for over 30,000 technicians. Maintained user communication to monitor issues and gathered feedback on features. Ensured continuous review, refactoring, and documentation of the codebase to enforce best practices.

 $Associate\ Software\ Engineer$

April 2018 - March 2020

- Instant Router Credentials Developed the integration of router setup credential services with current apps, allowing technicians to retrieve and update customers' internet router credentials instantly.
- Posture Helper Hackathon Conducted user research to identify a major issue faced by technicians in AT&T vans chronic pains from bad posture while sitting at work. Architected technical solutions using mobile apps with computer vision, achieving 3rd place out of 15 teams in an AT&T Hackathon.
- Development & Collaboration Worked closely with cross-functional teams and stakeholders to ensure better UI/UX. Crafted UML for clear communication and integrations across platforms in Enterprise architecture. Incorporated Scrum methodology for efficient project execution. Deployed and monitored features, logs, and APIs with Azure, Kubernetes, and Jenkins.

Consulting

Spice IT Global | Co-Founder

Nov 2023 – Present

- Pickle Video Journal App— Journaling app for everyone to craft their skills to the next level.
- Tempus Training App for Athletes— IOS app to help softball coaches train athlete's mental clock in game.

Graphics & Data Animation | Explorative Projects

April 2023 – Present

- Generate visuals and animations with JavaScript's canvas-sketch library to create engaging web graphics.
- Create interactive data visualization using D3 to display relationships between multiple geographic statistics.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA

BS in Computer Science, GPA 3.4/4.0

Aug. 2016 - May 2019

Georgia State University

Atlanta, GA

BA in Film. Minor in Music. Associate's in CS, Dean's List

Aug. 2006 - May 2010, Aug. 2016 - May 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, Swift, Python, SQL (Postgres), HTML/CSS, Java

Frameworks: Angular, React, SwiftUI, UIKit, Express.js, NestJS, Flask, Spring

Environments: Node.js

Developer Tools: Git, Kubernetes, Docker, Azure, VS Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Postman